The true story of an American ninja.
Bloodsport is a action, thriller, drama film directed by Newt Arnold.
An American Army Major goes AWOL to Hong Kong for an
outlawed martial arts contest called the Kumite.
Frank Dux, played by Jean-Claude Van Damme.
Chong Li, played by Bolo Yeung Sze.
Ray Jackson, played by Donald Gibb.
Janice Kent, played by Leah Ayres.
Helmer, played by Norman Burton.
Rawlins, played by Forest Whitaker.
Bloodsport is a 1988 American martial arts film directed by Newt Arnold and starring Jean-Claude Van Damme, with a
supporting cast of Leah Ayres, Donald Gibb, Roy Chiao, Norman Burton, Forest Whitaker, and Bolo Yeung.
The film centers on Frank Dux (Van Damme), a United States Army Captain and ninjutsu practitioner who
competes in an underground full-contact martial arts tournament called the Kumite in Hong Kong.
Based on Dux's real-life claims, the film was marketed as a true story.
It was one of Van Damme's first lead roles and showcased his
abilities, launching his career as a mainstream action star.
The screenplay is based on many of Dux's claims first covered in
the November 1980 issue of Black Belt magazine.
The real Dux served as the action choreographer and technical advisor.
After its release, many of Dux's claims were disputed, including by co-screenwriter Sheldon Lettich,
who claimed Dux fabricated his fight record and the very existence of the Kumite.
Bloodsport was produced and released by Cannon Films on February 26, 1988.
Despite negative critical reviews, it was a considerable box office
success, grossing $50 million on a budget of $1.5–2.3 million.
The success of the film helped the resurgence of the martial arts film genre in America, and
has been credited with influencing the development of mixed martial arts.
It has also been identified as a cult classic and spawned a film series
which includes four sequels, without Van Damme's involvement.
The film explores themes of martial arts, sports, biography, fistfight, sensei.
The tone is emotional and intense.